https://crwhite.ml 847-828-3885 201 Mission Street San Francisco, CA 94105 colin@abacus.ai

Colin White

RESEARCH INTERESTS I am interested in automating, explaining, and de-biasing deep learning models, from both a theoretical and empirical lens. Much of my work involves designing innovative methods by drawing insights from large-scale studies and designing tools for better benchmarking of machine learning techniques.

EXPERIENCE

Abacus.AI, San Francisco, CA

Head of Research and Distinguished Scientist

Head of Research

Research Scientist

Oct. 2022 – Present

Oct. 2020 – Oct. 2022

May 2019 – Oct. 2020

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D. in Computer Science Sep. 2014 – Dec. 2018

Advisor: Maria-Florina Balcan

Thesis committee: Avrim Blum, Anupam Gupta, Yury Makarychev, and David Woodruff

Amherst College, Amherst, MA

Double Major in Computer Science and Mathematics Sep. 2010 – May 2014

GPA: 3.76/4.0

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS Program Chair for AutoML-Conf 2023

2023

2022

Local Chair and Area Chair for AutoML-Conf 2022 Organizer for the AutoML Workshop at ICML 2021

2021

SELECTED HONORS AND AWARDS Top 10% of reviewers at NeurIPS 2020, 2021, 2022

 $2020 - 2022 \ 2021 - 2022$

Top 10% of reviewers at ICML 2021, 2022

2022

Top 10% of reviewers at ICLR 2022 $2^{\rm nd}$ place at the CVPR NAS unseen data competition (77 submissions)

Jun. 2021

National Defense Science & Engineering (NDSEG) Fellowship

Sep. 2014 – Dec. 2018

Amherst Memorial Fellowship

Sep. 2016 – Aug. 2017

John Woodruff Simpson Fellowship

Sep. 2014 - Aug. 2016

Post-Baccalaureate Summer Research Fellowship, Amherst College

Sep. 2014

Computer Science Prize (best thesis), Amherst College

May 2014

Henry F. Dunbar Award, Amherst College Swimming and Diving Team

May 2014

Summa Cum Laude (highest university honors), Amherst College

May 2014

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

For all publications, "With X, Y, Z" denotes alphabetically ordered authors, and \ast denotes equal contribution.

"k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience." With Maria-Florina Balcan and Nika Haghtalab. Transactions on Algorithms (TALG) 2020.

"Small dynamical heights for quadratic polynomials and rational functions." With Rob Benedetto, Ruqian Chen, Trevor Hyde, and Yordanka Kovacheva. Experimental Mathematics, 2014.

Conference Publications "NAS-Bench-Suite-Zero: Accelerating Research on Zero Cost Proxies"

Arjun Krishnakumar*, <u>Colin White</u>*, Arber Zela*, Renbo Tu*, Mahmoud Safari, Frank Hutter

Neural Information Processing Systems Datasets Track (NeurIPS Datasets), 2022.

"On the Generalizability and Predictability of Recommender Systems" Duncan McElfresh*, Sujay Khandagale*, Jonathan Valverde*, John P. Dickerson, <u>Colin White Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)</u>, 2022.

"A Deeper Look at Zero-Cost Proxies for Lightweight NAS"

<u>Colin White</u>, Mikhail Khodak, Renbo Tu, Shital Shah, Sébastien Bubeck, Debadeepta Dey

<u>International Conference on Learning Representations Blog Post Track (ICLR Blog Post)</u> 2022

"NAS-Bench-Suite: NAS Evaluation is (Now) Surprisingly Easy"

Yash Mehta*, <u>Colin White</u>*, Arber Zela, Arjun Krishnakumar, Guri Zabergja, Shakiba Moradian, Mahmoud Safari, Kaicheng Yu, Frank Hutter

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022.

"Synthetic Benchmarks for Scientific Research in Explainable Machine Learning" Yang Liu*, Sujay Khandagale*, <u>Colin White</u>, Willie Neiswanger Neural Information Processing Systems Datasets Track (NeurIPS Datasets), 2021.

"NAS-Bench-x11 and the Power of Learning Curves" Shen Yan*, <u>Colin White</u>*, Yash Savani, Frank Hutter Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.

"How Powerful are Performance Predictors in Neural Architecture Search?" Colin White, Arber Zela, Binxin Ru, Yang Liu, Frank Hutter.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.

"Exploring the Loss Landscape in Neural Architecture Search" Colin White, Sam Nolen, Yash Savani.

Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2021.

"BANANAS: Bayesian Optimization with Neural Architectures for Neural Architecture Search." Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Yash Savani.

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021.

"A Study on Encodings for Neural Architecture Search." Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Sam Nolen, Yash Savani.

Selected for spotlight presentation.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.

"Intra-Processing Methods for Debiasing Neural Networks." Yash Savani, <u>Colin White</u>, Naveen Govindarajulu. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.

"Robust Communication-Optimal Distributed Clustering Algorithms." With Pranjal Awasthi, Ainesh Bakshi, Maria-Florina Balcan, and David Woodruff. International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP) 2019.

"Data-Driven Clustering via Parameterized Lloyd's Families."

With Maria-Florina Balcan and Travis Dick.

Selected for spotlight presentation.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2018.

"Learning-Theoretic Foundations of Algorithm Configuration for Combinatorial Partitioning Problems."

With Maria-Florina Balcan, Vaishnavh Nagarajan, and Ellen Vitercik. Conference on Learning Theory (COLT) 2017.

"Data Driven Resource Allocation for Distributed Learning." With Travis Dick, Mu Li, Krishna Pillutla, Maria-Florina Balcan, and Alex Smola. International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS) 2017.

"Learning Combinatorial Functions from Pairwise Comparisons."

With Maria-Florina Balcan and Ellen Vitercik.

Conference on Learning Theory (COLT) 2016.

"k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience."

With Maria-Florina Balcan and Nika Haghtalab.

International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP) 2016.

"Lower Bounds in the Preprocessing and Query Phases of Routing Algorithms." Colin White.

European Symposium on Algorithms (ESA) 2015.

Theses

"New Aspects of Beyond Worst-Case Analysis."

Colin White.

Ph.D. Thesis, Carnegie Mellon University, 2018.

"Lower Bounds in the Preprocessing and Query Phases of Routing Algorithms."

Colin White.

Undergraduate Thesis, Amherst College, 2014.

WORKSHOP PUBLICATIONS "AutoML for Climate Change: A Call to Action"

Renbo Tu, Nicholas Roberts, Vishak Prasad, Sibasis Nayak, Paarth Jain, Frederic Sala, Ganesh

Ramakrishnan, Ameet Talwalkar, Willie Neiswanger, Colin White

NeurIPS Workshop on Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning, 2022

"On the Importance of Architectures and Hyperparameters for Fairness in Face Recognition" Rhea Sukthanker*, Samuel Dooley*, John P. Dickerson, <u>Colin White</u>, Frank Hutter, Micah Goldblum NeurIPS Workshop on Meta Learning, 2022, and

NeurIPS Workshop on Trustworthy and Socially Responsible Machine Learning, 2022.

"Speeding up NAS with Adaptive Subset Selection"

Vishak Prasad, <u>Colin White</u>, Paarth Jain, Sibasis Nayak, Rishabh Iyer, Ganesh Ramakrishnan *AutoML-Conf Late-Breaking Workshop*, 2022.

"On the Generalizability and Predictability of Recommender Systems" Duncan McElfresh*, Sujay Khandagale*, Jonathan Valverde*, John P. Dickerson, Colin White AutoML-Conf Late-Breaking Workshop, 2022.

"Synthetic Benchmarks for Scientific Research in Explainable Machine Learning" Yang Liu*, Sujay Khandagale*, <u>Colin White</u>, Willie Neiswanger *ICML Workshop on Explainable AI*, 2021.

"NAS-Bench-x11 and the Power of Learning Curves" Shen Yan*, <u>Colin White</u>*, Yash Savani, Frank Hutter CVPR Workshop on Neural Architecture Search, 2021.

"How Powerful are Performance Predictors in Neural Architecture Search?" Colin White, Arber Zela, Binxin Ru, Yang Liu, Frank Hutter.

Selected as a contributed talk.

ICLR Workshop on Neural Architecture Search, 2021.

"A Study on Encodings for Neural Architecture Search." <u>Colin White</u>, Willie Neiswanger, Sam Nolen, Yash Savani. *ICML Workshop on AutoML*, 2020.

"Local Search is State of the Art for Neural Architecture Search Benchmarks." <u>Colin White,</u> Sam Nolen, Yash Savani. *ICML Workshop on AutoML*, 2020. "Neural Architecture Search via Bayesian Optimization with a Neural Network Prior."

Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Yash Savani.

NeurIPS Workshop on Meta Learning, 2019.

"Deep Uncertainty Estimation for Model-based Neural Architecture Search."

Colin White, Willie Neiswanger, Yash Savani.

NeurIPS Workshop on Bayesian Deep Learning, 2019.

"DECO: Debiasing through Compositional Optimization of Machine Learning Models."

Naveen Govindarajulu, Colin White.

NeurIPS Workshop on Robust AI in Financial Services, 2019.

"Differentiable Functions for Combining First-order Constraints with Deep Learning via Weighted Proof Tracing."

Naveen Govindarajulu, Colin White.

NeurIPS Workshop on Knowledge Representation to ML, 2019.

"Data Driven Resource Allocation for Distributed Learning."

With Travis Dick, Mu Li, Krishna Pillutla, Maria-Florina Balcan, and Alex Smola.

AAAI Workshop on Distributed Machine Learning, 2019.

"An Improved Parallel Iterative Algorithm for Stable Matching."

Colin White, Enyue Lu.

 $SuperComputing\ Poster,\ 2013.$

Abacus. AI Mentor for early-career researchers

SELECTED TALKS	Neural Architecture Search: The Next Frontier. Tutorial at AutoML Fall School 2022 (virtual). Microsoft Research Redmond (virtual). Tutorial with Debadeepta Dey at AutoML-Conf 2022 in Baltimore, MD. AutoML Seminar, ELLIS Berlin (virtual).	Oct. 2022 Aug. 2022 Jul. 2022 Nov. 2020
	Research Methodology. Judson University (virtual).	Nov. 2021
	AutoML: AI that Builds AI. PhxMobi Emerging Tech Festival (virtual).	Nov. 2021
	AutoML Panel Discussion. AutoML Seminar, ELLIS Berlin and Freiburg, Germany (virtual). NAS Workshop at ICLR 2021 (virtual).	Oct. 2021 May 2021
	An Introduction to Neural Architecture Search. Abacus.AI webinar. Abacus.AI workshop. AICamp webinar.	Oct. 2020 Dec. 2019 Jul. 2019
	Data-Driven Clustering via Parameterized Lloyd's Families. Automated Algorithms Seminar at CMU.	May 2018
	Robust Communication-Optimal Distributed Clustering Algorithms. Theory Lunch Seminar at CMU.	Apr. 2017
	k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience. Simons Institute BWCA Workshop. Theory Lunch Seminar at CMU. Machine Learning Dept. Journal Club Class at CMU. Dagstuhl Workshop on Learning Theory.	Nov. 2016 Sep. 2016 Sep. 2016 Aug. 2015
Mentoring	Deep Learning Indaba Mentor for early-career researchers	2022 - Present
	LatinX AI (LXAI) Mentor for early-career researchers	2021 - Present

2019 - Present

SERVICE	Journal reviewer for JMLR, TPAMI, TALG, Algorithmica Conference reviewer for NeurIPS, ICML, ICLR, AISTATS, AAAI, UAI, FOCS, STOC, SODA, ITCS	2015 – Present 2015 – Present
	Doctoral Review Committee Member, CMU A panel of graduate students and faculty who oversee the Ph.D. program	2015 - 2018
	$\mathit{FreeCSD},$ a social organization for the Ph.D. department at CMU	2015 - 2018
	Theory Lunch Organizer, CMU	2016
	Ph.D. Admitted Students Open House Organizer, CMU	2016